It's time to take a stand.
Bully is a documentary, drama film directed by Lee Hirsch.
This year, over 5 million American kids will be bullied at school, online, on the bus, at home, through their cell phones and on
the streets of their towns, making it the most common form of violence young people in this country experience.
The Bully Project is the first feature documentary film to show how we've all been affected by
bullying, whether we've been victims, perpetrators or stood silent witness.
The world we inhabit as adults begins on the playground.
The Bully Project opens on the first day of school.
For the more than 5 million kids who'll be bullied this year in the United States,
it's a day filled with more anxiety and foreboding than excitement.
As the sun rises and school busses across the country overflow with backpacks, brass instruments
and the rambunctious sounds of raging hormones, this is a ride into the unknown.
self, played by Kirk Smalley.
Bully (originally titled The Bully Project) is a 2011 American documentary film
directed by Lee Hirsch and produced by Hirsch and Cynthia Lowen.
It documents the lives of five students who face
bullying on a daily basis in U.S.
The film premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival on April 23, 2011.
On the film's official website, the filmmakers promoted Bully as a tool to help combat bullying and facilitate an anti-bullying
movement, but these goals were jeopardized by its initial R rating from the Motion Picture Association of America.
Following a failed appeal of the rating, the Weinstein Company released the
film unrated in theaters in the United States on March 30, 2012.
After some profanity was removed, the film was re-rated PG-13, and this
version of the film was released in theaters on April 13.
The PG-13 version of the film was released on Blu-ray and DVD
nearly a year later, on February 12, 2013.
The film explores themes of florida, bullying, based on true story, 1990s.
The tone is emotional.